Science goes astray!
Frankenweenie is a animation, comedy, family film directed by Tim Burton.
When a car hits young Victor's pet dog Sparky, Victor decides to
bring him back to life the only way he knows how.
But when the bolt-necked "monster" wreaks havoc and terror in the hearts of Victor's
neighbors, he has to convince them that Sparky's still the good, loyal friend he was.
Mrs. Frankenstein / Weird Girl / Gym Teacher
(voice), played by Catherine O'Hara.
Mr. Frankenstein / Mr. Burgemeister / Nassor (voice), played by Martin Short.
Mr. Rzykruski (voice), played by Martin Landau.
Victor Frankenstein (voice), played by Charlie Tahan.
Edgar 'E' Gore (voice), played by Atticus Shaffer.
Elsa Van Helsing (voice), played by Winona Ryder.
Frankenweenie (also known as Tim Burton's Frankenweenie) is a 2012 American stop-motion animated Gothic comedy film directed by Tim Burton, written by
John August, and featuring the voices of Catherine O'Hara, Martin Short, Martin Landau, Charlie Tahan, Atticus Shaffer, and Winona Ryder.
A co-production between Walt Disney Pictures and Tim Burton Productions,
it is a feature-length remake of the 1984 short film.
The film follows a boy named Victor Frankenstein who uses the power of electricity to resurrect his dead dog Sparky, but his
peers discover what he has done and reanimate their own deceased pets and other creatures, resulting in mayhem.
Frankenweenie initially began development in November 2005, with a
script written by Josann McGibbon and Sara Parriott.
In December 2007, Burton was asked to direct two 3D films for Disney,
including a 2010 live-action adaptation of Alice in Wonderland.
Filming began at 3 Mills Studios in July 2010.
The tongue-in-cheek film contains numerous references to and parodies of Frankenstein and past film versions of it, other
literary classics, various horror and science-fiction films, and other films which Burton has directed or produced.
Frankenweenie premiered at Fantastic Fest on September 20, 2012, and was released in the United
States on October 5, to generally positive reviews for its visuals and story.
It was a moderate box office success, grossing
$82 million against a $39M budget.
It won the Saturn Award for Best Animated Film, and was nominated for an Academy
Award, a Golden Globe, a BAFTA, and an Annie Award for Best Animated Film.
The film explores themes of shyness, stop motion,
dog, animal death, animal lover.
The tone is lighthearted.